3 
 confusion of the issues, or misleading the jury. Courts have consistently held that 
evidence with a high potential for prejudice should be excluded to ensure a fair trial.  
 
Additionally, Wyoming case law reinforces these principles. In  Wyoming v. U.S. 
Department of Energy , 2006 WL 3801910 (D. Wyo. 2006), the court emphasized the importance 
of preventing jury confusion and undue prejudice. In  Holland v. Keller , 2018 WL 2446162 (D. 
Wyo. 2018), the court ruled that inflammatory evidence should be excluded , reinforcing the need 
to maintain a fair and impartial trial environment.  Further,  United States v. Hargrove , 2019 WL 
2516279 (D. Wyo. 2019), reiterated that evidence likely to cause unfair prejudice should be 
excluded  if it outweighs its probative value . Similarly, Meyer v. City of Cheyenne , 2017 WL 
3461055 (D. Wyo. 2017), highlighted that the use of terms that could unduly influence a jury Æs 
perception of a party should be excluded to preserve the integrity of the trial process.  Evidence is 
unfairly  prejudicial if it has ôan undue tendency to suggest [a] decision on an improper basis, 
commonly,  though not necessarily, an emotional one.ö U.S. v. Caraway , 534 F.3d 1290, 1301 
(10th Cir. 2008) (quoting Rule 402 adv. comm. notes).  
ARGUMENT  
I. PLAINTIFFS Æ MOTION IN LIMINE #1 : Evidence or commentary regarding 
ôsmok ing shed ö. 
 
Throughout this litigation, Defendants have made it a point to refer to the yellow shed 
outside of the boy Æs bedroom window as the  "smoking shed" . So much so, that every one of 
Defendants Æ experts used the term smoking shed through out their reports and deposition testimony. 
The shed was not manufactured as a smoking shed , it was not named a smoking shed, and it is not 
sold as a smoking shed.  It is obvious that Defendants Æ use of the term smoking shed , at every 
oppo rtunity , is only intended to exacerbate the s ensibilities of a jury to evoke unnecessary 
emotional responses and biases  from them , with the r esult being their inevitable inability to make Case 2:23-cv-00118-KHR     Document 141     Filed 01/22/25     Page 3 of 9
